today I'm gonna show you guys how to
create a basic eye makeup look and share
some my favorite tips and tricks I've
already prepped the lid with a little
bit of eyeshadow primer but you can use
foundation concealer whatever works for
you I've also left my lid slightly tacky
this will grab hold of the eyeshadow but
for beginners I would recommend setting
with a little bit of powder this will
give you a easier blend I often get
asked about the parts of the eye I'm
probably the main part that you need to
be aware of is the crease area this is
basically where the lid creases into the
eye shape but it often refers to
anything above this but below the brow
bone try not to over complicate it so
just make sure you're playing close
attention to your blend in the crease as
long as you leave a gap underneath your
brows you're good to go and the easiest
way to create a me eye makeup look is to
use a shadow at least one shade lighter
than your skintone a mid-tone shade and
then a shadow at least one shade darker
than your skin tone your mid-tone is
actually the most important and it can
be a little tricky to pick so I actually
recommend using your favorite nude
lipstick as a guide if it looks great on
your lips chances are it'll work in your
crease too
but just use a corresponding eye shadow
to match it we're gonna start off with
our mid-tone so choose whatever works
for you and we're using a blending brush
to start with this is anything with a
fluffy finish we're going to start this
in the crease of the eye
so apply this from the outer corner
working over a Mac above the lid
making sure to leave a gap just
underneath the brow bone
and also remember to keep your eyes open
this will help you figure out the shape
that you're creating
for hooded eyes this is a great way to
camouflage any hooded Ness as almost
contours the hooded Nyssa way if you
don't know where to stop and start your
eyeshadows use your brow edge of your
eye and edge of your nose as a guide and
blend in from this point as long as
you're blending in it will complement
your eye shape
and this area is where we've applied or
midtone we can now move on to contour
your contour shade is at least one shade
darker than your skin tone but can be
anywhere up to a black shade we're going
to apply it with that same brush and
keep this on the outer lid and into the
deep part of the crease
for a more precise application squash
down your fluffy brush and get it deep
in that crease this will prevent you
from bringing your contour up too high
which is a very beginner mistake to make
once you've applied it in that area open
up the brush and blend over and back
remember to keep your brush high on the
face this will make sure that your
contour doesn't blend too high and
they'll keep it nice and low and deep in
that crease the higher the hand the
lower the blend
and as you can see your contour ends up
within the area that you've mid-tone
your mid-tone is always the highest so
make sure to keep that contour it nice
and low now we're going to take a flat
brush this is anything with a smooth
flat line and we're gonna use this to
apply our highlighter shade which is
about one shade lighter than your skin
tone you're gonna apply this on the
inner corner of the lid focusing really
close to that inner edge and then
blending across the lid I like to do a
sweeping down motion across the lid
while the other eyeshadows have been
blending up and over this will give you
a cleaner finish you can also then take
something with a little bit of shimmer
and just Pat this over the top of the
lighter map shade
and there you go that is the finished
look super easy basic eye makeup look
that you can then adapt to work for you
finish off in whatever way that you want
and if you have any questions I am
always here to help so leave a comment
hit that like button make sure to
subscribe and I'll see you guys in the
next one